#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/johnniehuss (LinkedIn) www.johnniehuss.com (Company)

### Top Skills

Product Development
Creative Direction
Game Development

Languages Spanish

# John N.

Art Director at Meta

Los Angeles, California, United States

## Summary

I am an Art Director and Project Lead currently working in the realtime XR (AR/VR) space. I mix my technical production background and development experience with a design and user-focused creative eye to help interactive and realtime experiences and games look stunning and feel delightful.

I've spent a career working with global brands and am fluent in both Client and Internal, but I most enjoy working with creatives of all stripes. If you're serious about building amazing products / cool stuff / neat ideas - do reach out and say hello!

## Experience

Meta

3 years 10 months

Art Director

January 2021 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

Art Director | Portal Creative Engineering | Facebook Reality Labs July 2019 - Present (3 years 10 months)

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area

Helping to define, direct and implement visually arresting, compelling and toneappropriate AR experiences across platforms while working collaboratively with multi-disciplinary teams and external partners.

#### Facebook

Designer | 3d | AR - FB Messenger Art Team June 2018 - Present (4 years 11 months)

Menlo Park, CA

Conceive, design and execute engaging and enjoyable user-focused interactive Augmented Reality experiences - working to balance aesthetic quality with technical efficiency under real-time constraints.

Joba Media Art Director, Designer, 3d Artist + Partner June 2017 - May 2018 (1 year)

Greater Los Angeles Area

www.johnniehuss.com

Freelance 3d designer, generalist and art director providing design, concepting, and 3d character development, 3d vfx generalist work (modeling, sculpting, lookdev, grooming using xgen, ornatrix or yeti, ncloth, lighting, rendering in vray or redshift), asset development for mobile and game platforms, as well as limited rigging and animation, cg lead duties and nuke compositing. My work thus far in 2018 has encompassed 3d character design and development for mobile AR as well as generalist and lead roles lighting, rendering, rigging, animating and compositing on a range of projects...

We Are Royale
3d Generalist / Designer
January 2018 - March 2018 (3 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Freelance design and 3d contributions using Maya / Vray, Modo, Zbrush and Nuke to deliver on campaigns for Pepsi and Oculus. Modeling, UVs, rigging, animation, lookdey, lighting, rendering, compositing, etc...

Buck Senior 3D Generalist, Staff January 2014 - June 2017 (3 years 6 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

Senior 3d generalist assuming a variety of roles within a tightly integrated team of artists in the 3d department. Carried a range of responsibilities contingent on project-need, from self-directed 3d design, R&D, and leadership to core team-based roles, working with immediate team-members as well as crossfunctional partners in design to solve new creative challenges.

Zoic Studios
3d Generalist / Lighting Lead
September 2013 - January 2014 (5 months)
Culver City, CA

Provided a range of 3d work (modeling, texture painting, lighting, rendering, compositing) on a variety of projects for broadcast and web including

advertising campaigns for St. Ives and various ABC episodics including Once Upon a Time. Toolkit: Maya, Vray, Zbrush, Mudbox, Nuke.

John Niehuss
CG Lead / Lighting TD / 3D Generalist
May 2011 - January 2014 (2 years 9 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

In 2011 I went freelance for a few years and worked around the LA area as a 3d Generalist / Lighting TD at a variety of studios on a range of projects in TV and film - providing 3d animation, design, consulting, asset creation as well as occasional style-framing and other miscellaneous creative tasks...

Psyop 3D Generalist May 2013 - August 2013 (4 months) Los Angeles

Carried out various 3d tasks (modeling, look development, animation, lighting, rendering, shot assembly, compositing) on a number of high profile projects for clients including Microsoft and FEMA. 3d generalist toolkit included: Vray, Arnold, Maya, Modo, Nuke, Mudbox, etc.

Digital Domain 3.0 Senior 3d Artist, Level DA 1 January 2010 - December 2012 (3 years) Los Angeles

3d feature film lookdev, lighting and rendering using Maya / Vray as well as Maya / Renderman / SLIM and Maya / Arnold. Other work included productions using katana and various proprietary tools. Work also included lightbike animation on Tron: Legacy as well as hair grooming using proprietary hair tool Samson during Oblivion. Worked as core team member on films such as Tron: Legacy, Reel Steel, Enders Game Internal Test, Thor, Jack The Giant Slayer, Oblivion, etc providing a range of duties beyond lighting / rendering.

Motion Theory
3d Generalist / Digital Artist
December 2009 - February 2010 (3 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Contributed 3d generalist duties such as lookdev, animation, lighting, shot management, and rendering for advertising campaigns for Buick.

Sway Studio
Digital Artist
September 2009 - December 2009 (4 months)

3d Generalist using 3ds Max / Vray. Contributed lookdev, animation, scene management, lighting, rendering and comp to 3d car projects including all exterior lighting and rendering shots for GMC Terrain.

Buck

CG Supervisor April 2008 - January 2009 (10 months)

3d generalist responsible for a range of 3d-related tasks assuming a variety of roles within a tightly integrated team of artists in the 3d department. Carried a range of responsibilities depending on the needs of the project from self-directed 3d leadership and oversight to roles as a core team member taking direction from other team leaders. Delivered 3d work running the gamut of the 3d production pipeline - modeling, texturing, shading, animation, lighting, rendering, and compositing before moving on to CG Supervisor duties. Daily strategized with other 3d department leads regarding 3d pipeline, design, workflow, software and hiring.

Digital Domain
3d Generalist, DA 1
March 2006 - April 2008 (2 years 2 months)

3d generalist in DD Commercials on and off since 2005 using Lightwave, 3ds Max / Vray and Maya. Contributed myriad 3d and 2d work as needed on over 14 commercials, multiple internal bids, tests and pitches. Duties included team leadership, configuration management, modeling, UV mapping, look development, texture painting, matte painting, animation, lighting, rendering and compositing. Regularly handled all aspects of 3d from conception to comp.

Maas Digital 3d Generalist | Matte Painter 2003 - 2005 (2 years) Ithaca, New York Area

Key member of a VES award-winning four-artist team creating 4k 3d-rendered visuals for Disney's 2004 IMAX documentary film 'Roving Mars'. Created matte paintings, 16k textures, mechanical animation and hero hard-surface NASA vehicle models as well as various 2d and 3d environment work. Additionally, I contributed various 2d tasks and 3d generalist work on projects for PBS

and AeroVironment Inc. including modeling, UV mapping, texture and matte painting, lookdev, animation, and lighting.

## Education

## Occidental College

Bachelor's degree, Film/Video and Photographic Arts · (September 2002 - June 2005)

## Occidental College

Bachelor's Degree, Film/Cinema/Video Studies · (2002 - 2005)

### **Pratt Institute**

NA, Illustration / Computer Graphics · (2000 - 2001)

#### **Pratt Institute**

N/A Transfer, Computer Graphics · (2000 - 2001)